Guide to the William Richard Johnson Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Correspondence, 1836-1966, n.d.; Series I; 7' (26 boxes)
  - Correspondence: General
    - Incl. to/fr: American Consul General, Bishop Birney, fr: George T. Blydenburgh, re: conditions at Nanchang, 1926 Oct-Dec (Box 13, Folder 225)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Birney, American Consular Service, fr: G.T. Blyden burgh, to: Sen. Wm. E. Borah re: Revolt, IBJ and children return to USA, 1927 Jan-Feb (Box 13, Folder 226)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Birney, re: revolt and leaving Nanchang, 1927 Mar-May (Box 13, Folder 227)
    - Incl. to/fr: C.K. Shaw, Bishop Birney, re: WRJ and son returning to USA, 1927 Jun-Jul (Box 13, Folder 228)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Birney, re: News from China, 1927 Aug-Oct (Box 13, Folder 229)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Birney, re: Conditions in China, 1927 Nov-Dec (Box 13, Folder 230)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Birney, fr: F.R. Brown, W.A. Main, C.K. Shaw, re: Famine Relief, 1928 Jan-Jun (Box 14, Folder 231)
    - Incl. fr: Bishop Birney, F.R. Brown, W. Schubert, C.K. Shaw, re: Famine Relief, 1928 Aug-Dec (Box 14, Folder 232)
    - Incl. fr: Bishop Birney, F.R. Brown, C.K. Shaw, re: Columbia University, Famine relief, 1929 Jan-Apr (Box 14, Folder 233)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Birney, re: Return to China, 1929 Jun-Dec (Box 14, Folder 234)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Birney, R.E. Diffendorfer, re: Famine Relief, 1930 Jan-Aug (Box 14, Folder 235)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Birney, To: R.E. Diffendorfer, fr: J.E. Baker, 1930 Sep-Dec (Box 14, Folder 236)
    - Incl. to/fr: J.C. Baker, Bishop Birney, Frank Cartwright, to: Editor, The China Press, 1931 Jan-Aug (Box 14, Folder 237)
    - Incl. re: Charges by L.S.C. Wang vs. WRJ, relief, Bishop Birney leaves China, 1931 Sep-Dec (Box 14, Folder 238)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Birney, to: J.C. Baker, re: Famine relief, charges against WRJ, illness of WRJ, 1932 Jan-Dec (Box 14, Folder 239)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Herbert Welch, re: Sale of land, Wang trial, Rural Reconstruction Project, 1933 Jan-Jun (Box 14, Folder 240)
    - Fr: Madame Chiang Kai-shek, 1933 Jun 10, Oct 7 (Box 14, Folder 241)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Welch, fr: Sec'y. of Madame Chiang, re: Rural Reconstruction Project, 1933 Jul-Oct (Box 14, Folder 242)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Welch, American Consul General ret property, Re: Gen. and Madame Chiang Kai-shek in Nanchang, 1933 Nov-Dec (Box 14, Folder 243)
    - Incl. to/fr: John Gowdy, Bishop Welch, fr: American Consul Gen., D.J. Fleming, H.W. Hering, IBJ, 1934 Jan-Aug (Box 14, Folder 244)
    - Incl. to/fr: J. Gowdy, Bishop Welch, re: Property, 1934 Sep-Dec (Box 14, Folder 245)
    - Fr: Madame Chiang Kai-shek, 1934 Dec 27 (Box 14, Folder 246)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Welch, re: Sale of property, 1935 Jan-Mar (Box 14, Folder 247)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Welch, to: Madame Chiang, fr: Sec'y. to Madame Chiang, re: hospital situation, 1935 Apr-Jul (Box 14, Folder 248)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Welch, fr: American Consul Gen., J. Gowdy,Sec'y. to Madame Chiang, re: expected rendition of the Kuling Estate, 1935 Aug-Dec (Box 14, Folder 249)
    - Incl. fr: Bishop Welch, C.K. Shaw, of Admin. for Lushan, re: finances, furlough, 1936 Jan-Jul (Box 15, Folder 250)
    - Incl. to: Adelaide Case, W.E. Hammaker Re: Study at Teachers' College, Columbia Univ., 1936 Sep-Dec (Box 15, Folder 251)
    - Incl. to/fr: W.E. Hammaker, fr: Dodd, Mead Co., re: East Asia Conference, 1937 Jan-Apr (Box 15, Folder 252)
    - Incl. to/fr: W.E. Hammaker, fr: American Consul Gen., Coral Houston, re: WRJ return to China, 1937 May-Sep (Box 15, Folder 253)
    - Incl. to/fr: W.E. Hammaker, re: missionaries leave Kuling, 1937 Oct-Dec (Box 15, Folder 254)
    - Incl. to/fr: W.E. Hammaker, fr: Madame Chiang Kai-shek, M.S. Bates, C.H. Riggs, re: bombing at Nanchang, 1938 Jan-Mar (Box 15, Folder 255)
    - Incl. to/fr: W.E. Hammaker, C.K. Shaw, re: refugee relief, Japanese bombers, 1938 Apr-Aug (Box 15, Folder 256)
    - Incl. to/fr: W.E. Hammaker, fr: C.K. Shaw, re: refugee relief work, 1938 Sep-Oct (Box 15, Folder 257)
    - Incl. to/fr: W.E. Hammaker, fr: C.K. Shaw, re: refugee work, war conditions, 1938 Nov-Dec (Box 15, Folder 258)
    - Incl. to/fr: L.R. Craighill, W.E. Hammaker, L.W. Holland, C.K. Shaw, 1939 Jan-Mar (Box 15, Folder 259)
    - Incl. fr: Cordell Hull, C.K. Shaw, re: fall of Nanchang, refugee work, L.W. Holland, 1939 Apr-Aug (Box 15, Folder 260)
    - Incl. to/fr: G.V. Fuller, fr: C.K. Shaw, re: Refugee Relief Assn., 1939 Sep-Oct (Box 15, Folder 261)
    - Incl. to/fr: G.V. Fuller, fr: C.K. Shaw, re: Yungfeng Camp, 1939 Nov-Dec (Box 15, Folder 262)
    - Incl. to/fr: Hwa Hsing Tung, to: Hsu Hsi Chi, Walter H. Judd, re: Famine relief, furlough, 1940 Jan-Apr (Box 15, Folder 263)
    - Incl. to/fr: R.S. Greene, to: S.K. Hornbeck, Louis Johnson, F.D. Roosevelt, E.R. Stettinius, Jr-, fr: C.K. Shaw, 1940 May-Aug (Box 15, Folder 264)
    - Incl. to/fr: J.E. Baker, F.T. Cart wright, R.S. Greene, fr: Bishop Ralph A. Ward, 1940 Aug-Nov (Box 15, Folder 265)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Ward, re: American Red Cross relief work, 1941 Jan-Nov (Box 16, Folder 266)
    - Incl. re: Fall of Hong Kong, Internment Camp, repatriation, 1942 Jan-Aug (Box 16, Folder 267)
    - Incl. to: Bishop Ward, ret Red Cross work, 1942 Sep (Box 16, Folder 268)
    - Incl. to/fr: Albert Evans, re: Red Cross work, 1942 Nov-Dec (Box 16, Folder 269)
    - Incl. fr: Dept. of State, Office of War Information, C.K. Shaw, 1942 Sep-Oct (Box 16, Folder 270)
    - Incl. fr: Carleton Lacy, re: Speaking engagements, 1943 Jan-Feb (Box 16, Folder 271)
    - Incl. fr: Gertrude Cone, re: Speaking engagements, 1943 Mar-Apr (Box 16, Folder 272)
    - Incl. to: Gertrude Cone, re: Speaking engagements, 1943 May (Box 16, Folder 273)
    - Incl. fr: J.E. Baker, Dept. of State re: Speaking engagements, 1943 Jun (Box 16, Folder 274)
    - Incl. to/fr: C.K. Shaw, fr: Gertrude Cone, Carleton Lacy, re: Speaking engagements, 1943 Jul-Aug (Box 16, Folder 275)
    - Incl. to/fr: J.E. Baker, to: C.K. Shaw re: Speaking engagements, 1943 Sep-Oct (Box 16, Folder 276)
    - Incl. to: J.E. Baker, fr: Gertrude Cone, C.K. Shaw, incl. Report on the Nanchang Academy 1937-1940, re: Speaking Engagements, 1943 Nov (Box 16, Folder 277)
    - Incl. re: Speaking engagements, 1943 Dec (Box 16, Folder 278)
    - Incl. re: Speaking engagements, 1944 Jan (Box 17, Folder 279)
    - Incl. to: C.K. Shaw, re: Speaking engagements, 1944 Feb (Box 17, Folder 280)
    - Incl. re: Speaking engagements, 1944 Mar (Box 17, Folder 281)
    - Incl. fr: Margaret Seeck, re: Speaking engagements, 1944 Apr-May (Box 17, Folder 282)
    - Incl. fr: C.K. Shaw, re: Speaking engagements, 1944 Jun (Box 17, Folder 283)
    - Incl. re: Speaking engagements, health of WRJ, 1944 Jul- Aug (Box 17, Folder 284)
    - Incl. fr: C.K. Shaw, re: Speaking Engagements, 1944 5ep-Oct (Box 17, Folder 285)
    - Incl. to/fr: Carleton Lacy, G.W. Shepherd, fr: C.K. Shaw, 1944 Nov (Box 17, Folder 286)
    - Incl. re: Speaking engagements, 1944 Dec (Box 17, Folder 287)
    - Incl. re: Speaking engagements, 1945 Jan-Feb (Box 17, Folder 288)
    - Incl. fr: Survey of Foreign Experts, C.K. Shaw, re: Retirement, Speaking engagements, 1945 Mar-Jun (Box 17, Folder 289)
    - Incl. to/fr: Alfred Kohlberg, G.W. Shepherd, to: Walter Judd, C.K. Shaw, Tao-ming, re: Speaking engagements, 1945 Jul-Sep (Box 17, Folder 290)
    - Incl. to/fr: A. Kohlberg, C.K. Shaw, J.E. Baker, to: Patrick J. Hurley, W. Judd, from: Wei Tao-ming, re: Job applications, 1945 Oct-Nov (Box 17, Folder 291)
    - Incl. to/fr: C.K. Shaw, fr: Dept. of State, Carleton Lacy, 1945 Dec (Box 17, Folder 292)
    - Incl. to/fr: A. Kohlberg, Time, re: Job with International Educational Publ. Co., 1946 Jan-Feb (Box 18, Folder 293)
    - Incl. to/fr: John B. Powell, W.H, Judd, C.K. Shaw, Time, fr: Carleton Lacy, J.E. Baker' re: job application, 1946 Mar-May (Box 18, Folder 294)
    - Incl. to/fr: A. Kohlberg, to: James F. Byrnes, fr: Paul Wang, re: Speaking engagements, "Manchurian Manifesto", 1946 Jun-Jul (Box 18, Folder 295)
    - Incl. to/fr: G. Fitch, Time, A.C. Wedemeyer, re: Speaking engagements, 1946 Aug (Box 18, Folder 296)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Ward, to: New York Times, 1946 Sep (Box 18, Folder 297)
    - Incl. to/fr: The China Monthly, to: C.K., re: Speaking engagements, A.C.P.A., 1946 Oct (Box 18, Folder 298)
    - Incl. to/fr: The China Monthly, fr: C.K. Shaw, re: Speaking engagements, 1946 Nov-Dec (Box 18, Folder 299)
    - To/fr: A.C.P.A., to: C.K. Shaw, fr: C. Lacy, re: Speaking engagements, 1947 Jan (Box 18, Folder 300)
    - Incl. to: Christian Century, A. Kohl berg, fr: L.E. Allen, Bishop Ward, 1947 Feb (Box 18, Folder 301)
    - Incl. to/fr: C.K. Shaw, to: Bishop Ward, fr: C. Lacy, Timothy Yang, 1947 Mar-Apr (Box 18, Folder 302)
    - Incl. to/fr: C.K. Shaw, A. Kohlberg, to: C.A. Eaton, A.H. Vandenberg, W.H. Judd, fr: J.E. Baker, W.B. Pettus, 1947 May-Jun (Box 18, Folder 303)
    - Incl. to/fr: A. Kohlberg, fr: C.K. Shaw, missionaries in China, 1947 Jul-Aug (Box 18, Folder 304)
    - Incl. to: A. Kohlberg, fr: Chinese Embassy, WRJ, G.W. Shepherd, re: A.C.P.A., 1947 Sep-Oct (Box 18, Folder 305)
    - Incl. to/fr: The China Monthly, the Chinese Embassy, A.H. Vandenberg, to: W.H. Judd, G.C. Marshall, fr: Kimber H.K. Den, 1947 Nov (Box 18, Folder 306)
    - Incl. to/fr: Chinese Embassy, to: E.D. Thomas, fr: C.K. Shaw, W. Walkinshaw, 1947 Dec (Box 18, Folder 307)
    - Incl. to/fr: J.E. Baker, E.D. Thomas, magazines, fr: Chinese Embassy, 1948 Jan (Box 19, Folder 308)
    - Incl. to/fr: W.H. Judd, E.D. Thomas, L.O., Chinese Embassy, fr: L.E. Allen, 1948 Feb-Mar (Box 19, Folder 309)
    - Incl. to/fr: Chinese Embassy, W.H. Judd, .D. Thomas, F.E. Spenser, re: MFSA, 1948 Apr (Box 19, Folder 310)
    - Incl. to: J. Parnell Thomas, A. Kohlberg: A.W. Barkley, J.G. Fulton, J.W. Powell, R.E. Stripling, E.D. Thomas, Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr., re: A.C.P.A., MFSA, 1948 May (Box 19, Folder 311)
    - Incl. to/fr: H.E. Capehart, To: J.W. Powell, re: MFSA, 1948 Jun-Jul (Box 19, Folder 312)
    - Incl. to/fr: C.K. Shaw, fr: J.W. Powell, Eleanor Roosevelt, re: A.C.P.A., 1948 Aug-Oct (Box 19, Folder 313)
    - Incl. to/fr: C.K. Shaw, Motive, to: W.H. Judd, J.C. Vincent, re: A.C.P.A., Speaking Engagements, 1948 Nov-Dec (Box 19, Folder 314)
    - Incl. to/fr: Various newspapers and magazines, A.H. Vandenberg, Chinese Embassy,: H. Freeman, FP Bolton, T. Connally, W. H. Judd, fr: J.D. Lodge, 1949 Jan-Feb (Box 19, Folder 315)
    - Incl. to/fr: Chinese Embassy, A. Kohlberg, to: W.H. Judd, T. Connally, New York Times, fr: P.H. Douglas, Brien Mc Mahon, A.F. Schoappel, 1949 Mar-Apr (Box 19, Folder 316)
    - Incl. to/fr: J.R. Jackson, A. Kohlberg, to: E.L. Smith, fr: Chinese Embassy, W.H. Judd E.L. Smith, Gertrude Cone, F.T., R.M. Cross, 1949 May (Box 19, Folder 317)
    - Incl. to/fr: J.R. Steelman, Mark Tsai, J.M. Henry, A. Kohlberg, fr: J.R. Jackson, F.T. Cartwright, to: Chinese Embassy, Open Letter to Bishop A.J. Moore, 1949 Jun-Jul (Box 19, Folder 318)
    - Incl. to/fr: A. Kohlberg, J.R. Steelman, to: W.H. Judd, fr: Chinese Embassy, J.M. Henry, J.R. Jackson, H. Welch, re: "An Open Letter to Bishop A.J. Moore", 1949 Aug-Oct (Box 19, Folder 319)
    - Incl. to/fr: L.B. Moody, to: The Christian Advocate, A. Kohlberg, fr: C. Lacy, J.M. Henry, F.T. Cartwright, China Central Conference, 1949 Nov-Dec (Box 19, Folder 320)
    - lncl. to: A. Kohlberg, Congressmen, the President, Christian Advocate, fr: congressmen, F.T. Cartwright, Kiangsi Christian Rural Service Union, 1950 Jan (Box 20, Folder 321)
    - Incl. to/fr: W.H. Judd, Chinese Embassy, to Defend America..., Time, fr: C.K. Shaw, Kiangsi Christian R.S.U., C. Lacy, F.T. Cartwright, re: A.C.P.A., 1950 Feb-May (Box 20, Folder 322)
    - Incl. to/fr: A. Kohlberg, Time, to: W.H. Judd, Chinese Embassy, Mark Tsai, R. Gwinn, fr: L.E. Allen, J. Lind, re: Mao-Stalin pact, Kiangsi Christian R.S.U., 1950 Jun-Jul (Box 20, Folder 323)
    - Incl. to/fr: A. Kohlberg, fr: China missionaries, re: "China, Key to the Orient", A.C.P.A.,Kiangsi Christian R.S.U., 1950 Aug-Sep (Box 20, Folder 324)
    - Incl. to: President of the United States, President of China, fr: Chinese Embassy, C.K. Shaw, re: publications, Kiangsi R.S.U., 1950 Oct (Box 20, Folder 325)
    - Incl. fr: Church League of America, re: Kiangsi Christian R.S.U., 1950 Nov (Box 20, Folder 326)
    - Incl. fr: Sec'y. to Madame Chiang Kai-shek, F.T. Cartwright, re: publications, Christian R.S.U., 1950 Dec (Box 20, Folder 327)
    - Incl. to/fr: E.A. Rumley, to: R.A. Gwinn, A. Kohlberg, H.P. VanDusen, fr: H.C. Lodge, Jr., Bishop Ward, W.A. Harrison, Ass't. to the Sec'y. of the Republic of China, re: publications, 1951 Jan (Box 20, Folder 328)
    - Incl. to/fr: A. A. Kohlberg, Chinese Embassy, to: W.F. Knowland, re: publications, speaking, 1951 Feb (Box 20, Folder 329)
    - Incl. to/fr: A. Kohlberg, R. Morris, G. Fitch, fr: F.T. Cartwright, re: publications, speaking, 1951 Mar (Box 20, Folder 330)
    - Incl. to/fr: L.E. Allan, E.A. Rumel, to: P.H. Douglas, Pres. of the United States, E.M. Dirksen, W.H. Judd, fr: Edna Lonigan, J.I. Dolliver, 1951 Apr (Box 20, Folder 331)
    - Incl. to/fr: E.A. Rumeley, E.M. Dirksen, T. Otto Nall, fr: P.H, Douglas, L. Robinson-F.T. Cartwright, re: A.C.P.A., publications, 1951 May-Jun (Box 20, Folder 332)
    - Incl. to/fr: A. Kohlberg, fr: E.M. Dirksen, T.O.Nall, re: publications, 1951 Jul-Aug (Box 20, Folder 333)
    - Incl. to/fr: E.M. Dirksen, A. Kohlberg, T.O. Nall, to: T. Lee, fr: F.Gale, G. Cone, Joseph McCarthy, E.A. Rumeley, re: publications, 1951 Sep-Oct (Box 20, Folder 334)
    - Incl. to/fr: T.O. Nall, L.E. Allen, to: T. Connally, fr: A. Kohlberg, G. Cone, re: publications, 1951 Nov-Dec (Box 20, Folder 335)
    - Incl. to/fr: E.A. Rameley, A. Kohlberg, to: J.H. Pew, Chinese Embassy, fr: T.O. Nall, L.H. Smith, re: publications, deaths of C. Lacy and G. Cone, 1952 Jan-Feb (Box 21, Folder 336)
    - Incl. to/fr: J.H. Pew, Chinese Embassy, A. Kohlberg, to: T.O. Nall, L.H. Smith, W.H. Judd, fr: F.P. Jones, J. Duvall, F. Gale, M. Atterbury, re: Publications death of G. Cone, 1952 Mar (Box 21, Folder 337)
    - Incl. to/fr: W.H. Judd, to: T.O. Nall, .S. Leiper, Harry S. Truman, A. Kohlberg, fr: E. Lonigan, J.H. Pew, re: Publications, Testimony before the Senate committee, 1952 Apr (Box 21, Folder 338)
    - Incl. to/fr: T.O. Nall, to: J.H. Pew, H. S. Leiper, re: publications, A.C.P.Ar, 1952 May-Jul (Box 21, Folder 339)
    - Incl. to/fr: T.O. Nall, A. Kohlberg, J.H. Pew, to: L.E. Allen, re: Publications, speaking, 1952 Aug-Oct (Box 21, Folder 340)
    - Incl. to: E.A. Rumeley, A. Kohlberg, Chinese Embassy, fr: Cartwright and Robinson, re: Publications, A.C.P.A., 1952 Nov-Dec (Box 21, Folder 341)
    - Incl. to/fr: A. Kohlberg, G. Shepherd, to: Chinese Embassy, re: Publications, 1953 Jan-Mar (Box 21, Folder 342)
    - Incl. to/fr: J.H. Pew, T.O. Nall, to: W.H. Judd, The President of the U.S., fr: Chinese Embassy, A. Kohlberg, re: A.C.P.A., Publications, 1953 Apr-Jun (Box 21, Folder 343)
    - Incl. to/fr: A. Kohlberg, T.O. Nall, L.E. Allen, to: J.H. Pew, fr: Sec'y. to J.H. Pew, G.W. Shepherd, Dept. of State, 1953 Jul-Aug (Box 21, Folder 344)
    - Incl. to/fr: J.H. Pew, W.E. Warner, re: Publications, ACCL, All-American Conference to Combat Communism, 1953 Sep-Oct (Box 21, Folder 345)
    - Incl. to/fr: A. Kohlberg, re: Publications, 1953 Nov-Dec (Box 21, Folder 346)
    - Incl. to/fr: Chinese Embassy, fr: L.E. Allen, re: Publications, A.C.P.A., ser mon by Paul L. McKay, 1954 Jan (Box 22, Folder 347)
    - Incl. fr: L.E. Allen, A. Kohlberg, E.M., J.W. Bricker, J.H. Pew, L.C. Scott, re: Publications, Committee on Un-American Activities, 1954 Feb-Apr (Box 22, Folder 348)
    - Incl. fr: Chinese Embassy, 1954 May-Aug (Box 22, Folder 349)
    - Incl. to/fr: A. Kohlberg, to: D.E. True blood, fr: Helen Keller, 1954 Sep-Dec (Box 22, Folder 350)
    - Incl. to/fr: T.P. Sheehan, to: Henry C. Lodge, W.H. Judd, 1955 Jan-Feb (Box 22, Folder 351)
    - Incl. to: W.F. George, J.F. Dulles, fr: W.H. Judd, 1955 Mar-Apr (Box 22, Folder 352)
    - Incl. to/fr: E.M. Dirksen, J.H. Pew, W. H. Judd, to: W.F. Knowland, Q.K.Y. Huang, G.W. Malone, fr: Dept. of State with pamphlet by J.F. Dulles, re: Class re union, 1955 May-Jun (Box 22, Folder 353)
    - Incl. fr: A. Kohlberg, Q.K.Y. Huang, T.I. Lee, 1955 Jul-Aug (Box 22, Folder 354)
    - Incl. to/fr: A. Kohlberg, to: Editor, Tri-County Press, 1955 Sep-Oct (Box 22, Folder 355)
    - Incl. to/fr: A. Kohlberg, H.C. Lodge, to: W.H. Pierce, J.F. Dulles, J.O. Eastland, fr: W.E. Jenner, 1955 Nov-Dec (Box 22, Folder 356)
    - Incl. to: H.C. Lodge, Jr.,fr: Dept. of State, J.O. Eastland, T.I. Lee, W.E. Jenner, R.W. Baird, W.G. Stratton, 1956 Jan-Feb (Box 23, Folder 357)
    - Incl. to/fr: T.I. Lee, FP Jones, fr: W.E. Jenner, J.O. Eastland, 1956 Mar-May (Box 23, Folder 358)
    - Incl. to/fr: A. Kohlberg, to: Styles Bridges, W.F. Knowland, W.H. Judd, W.E. Jenner, re: Publications, 1956 Jun-Aug (Box 23, Folder 359)
    - Incl. fr: A. Kohlberg, 1956 Sep-Oct (Box 23, Folder 360)
    - Incl. to/fr: Edgar C. Bundy, fr: A. Kohlberg, 1956 Nov-Dec (Box 23, Folder 361)
    - Incl. to/fr: W.F. Knowland, E.M. Dirksen, L.E. Allen, to: W.E. Jenner, fr: U.S' Mission to the U.N., 1957 Jan-Mar (Box 23, Folder 362)
    - Incl. to/fr: Ambassador of the Republic of China, to: J.F. Dulles, fr: Embassy of the Republic of China, G. Hwa Chu, Dept. of State, L.E. Allen, E.M. Dirksen, 1957 Apr-Aug (Box 23, Folder 363)
    - Incl. to/fr: R.W. Gwinn, Jen-chi Chang, A. Kohlberg, fr: P.H. Douglas, G. Fitch, L.E. Allen, to: Friends of J. H. Pew re: The Story of Mary Liu, 1957 Sep-Dec (Box 23, Folder 364)
    - Incl. to/fr: Ambassador of China, H.M., to: A. Kohlberg, J.F. Dulles, W.M. Jenner, fr: P.W. Broyles, 1958 Jan-Feb (Box 24, Folder 365)
    - Incl. to/fr: H.M. Bullock, E.C. Bundy, A. Kohlberg, fr: E.M. Dirksen, W.F. Knowland, 1958 Mar-Apr (Box 24, Folder 366)
    - Incl. to/fr: H.M. Bullock, W.E. Warner, W.E. Jenner, to: E.M. Dirksen, fr: L.E. Allen, W.L. Hays, 1958 May-Aug (Box 24, Folder 367)
    - Incl. to/fr: A. Kohlberg, to: The President of the U.S., J.F. Dulles, fr: The 't. to the President, Dept. of State, 1958 Sep-Nov (Box 24, Folder 368)
    - Incl. re: Christmas letters, death of Bishop Ward, 1958 Dec (Box 24, Folder 369)
    - Incl. fr: A. Kohlberg, Sky Powell, 1959 Jan-May (Box 24, Folder 370)
    - Incl. to/fr: F.R. Brown, Chun-gi Kwei, E.M. Dirksen, to: Pres. of the U.S., W.G. Stratton, fr: Ass't. to the Pres., P.H. Douglas, J.C. Thomson, Jr., 1959 Jun-Aug (Box 24, Folder 371)
    - Incl. to/fr: Chun-gi Kwei, J.W. Fulbright, J.C. Thomson, Jr., fr: A.M. Bentley with encl., P.H. Douglas with encl., re: visit of Nikita Khrushchev, 1959 Sep (Box 24, Folder 372)
    - Incl. to/fr: Chun-gi Kwei, to: E.C. Bundy, Jawaharlal Nehru, fr: E.M. Dirksen, 1959 Oct-Dec (Box 24, Folder 373)
    - Incl. to/fr: F. Jones, A. Kohlberg, Chun gi Kwei, fr: L.E. Allen, E.M. Dirksen, R. Arens, re: Non-recognition of Communist China, 1960 Jan-Mar (Box 24, Folder 374)
    - Incl. to/fr: R. Arens, FP Jones, fr: F.E. Walter, E.M. Dirksen, re: Non-recognition of Communist China, death of A. Kohlberg, 1960 Apr-May (Box 24, Folder 375)
    - Incl. to: Bishops and Delegates of the 1960 Methodist General Conference, Sec'y. of State, L.E. Allen, fr: FP Jones, W.H. Judd, 1960 Jun-Jul (Box 24, Folder 376)
    - Incl. to: Richard M. Nixon, To the Bishops and Delegates, 1960 Aug-Nov (Box 24, Folder 377)
    - Incl. re: Christmas letters, 1960 Dec (Box 24, Folder 378)
    - Incl. to: The Bishops and Delegates fr: J.R. Pillion, re: WRJ's bomb shelter, 1961 Jan-Jul (Box 25, Folder 379)
    - Incl. fr: P.H. Douglas, E.M. Dirksen, 1961 Aug (Box 25, Folder 380)
    - Incl. to: Federal Civil Defense Administration with encl. ret bomb shelter,: Award to WRJ from Republic of China, 1961 Sep (Box 25, Folder 381)
    - Incl. fr: Dept. of Defense, re: Award from China, 1961 Oct-Nov (Box 25, Folder 382)
    - Incl. to: Consul General F.T.T. Sia, re: Christmas letters, 1961 Dec (Box 25, Folder 383)
    - Incl. fr: Tracey K. Jones, Jr., J.B. Anderson, G. Fitch, re: American Jewish Anti-Communist League, 1962 Jan-Mar (Box 25, Folder 384)
    - Incl. to: W.H. Judd, fr: J.B. Anderson, 1962 Apr-Aug (Box 25, Folder 385)
    - Incl. to: Committee for the Monroe Doctrine, Kiangsi Friends, fr: J.B. Ander, sdn, 1962 Sep-Dec (Box 25, Folder 386)
    - Incl. to/fr: J.B. Anderson, to: Carl McIntire, fr: W.H. Judd, 1963 Jan-Jul (Box 25, Folder 387)
    - Incl. to/fr: Chicago Tribune Press Soc., P.H. Douglas, to: F.J. Laushe, fr: J.J. Williams, E.M. Dirksen, re: Death of Ina B. Johnson, 1963 Aug-Oct (Box 25, Folder 388)
    - Incl. to: P.M. Douglas, fr: E.M. Dirksen, re: Letters of condolence after death of IRJ, 1963 Nov-Dec (Box 25, Folder 389)
    - Incl. to/fr: J.B. Anderson, Northwestern Univ., fr: W.H. Judd, re: Letters of condolence, 1964 (Box 25, Folder 390)
    - [ncl. re: Estate of IBJ, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 391)
    - Incl. fr: W.H. Judd, Styles Bridges, re: Estate of IBJ, 1966 (Box 25, Folder 392)
    - A-D, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 393)
    - E-J, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 394)
    - William R. Johnson, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 395)
    - K-R, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 396)
    - S-W, Anonymous, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 397)
    - Fragments, 1910-1928 (Box 26, Folder 398)
    - Fragments, 1930-1946 (Box 26, Folder 399)
    - Fragments, 1947-1965 (Box 26, Folder 400)
    - Fragments A-W, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 401)
    - Fragments-William R. Johnson, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 402)
    - Fragments- Anonymous n.d. (Box 26, Folder 403)
    - Telegrams, 1910-1965 (Box 26, Folder 404)
    - Telegrams., n.d (Box 26, Folder 405)
- Writings and Printed Material, 1906-1961, n.d.; Series II; 3' 6" (9 boxes)
  Writings are divided into two categories: family and non-family. The first five boxes contain writings and printed material by William R. Johnson, followed by material written by other family members. Dated writings and printed material are filed first. Material without dates follows, filed alphabetically by title. Incomplete or untitled writings complete this category.
  Writings and printed material not written by William R. Johnson or family members are arranged chronologically. Undated writings are filed alphabetically by title after the dated material. Incomplete or untitled writings follow. Printed material such as church bulletins and Chinese language material completes this category.
  - List by WRJ: "Articles and Manuscripts" (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Incl. "H.C. Hwang," "By their Fruits You Shall Know Them", 1906-1908, 1913 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - "Nanchang Academy", 1916-1917 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Incl.: "Non-return of Wm. R. Johnson to Kiangsi, China", 1918-1920 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - "Famine Relief in Shantung", 1922 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Incl.: "A Chinese Bishop for the Chinese Church'', 1924 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - "Annual Report-Kiangsi International Famine Relief Committee," "Nanchang Academy Annual Report", 1925 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Bulletins re: war conditions, "Shall Missionaries Renounce Their Citizen ship?", 1926 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Bulletins, "Memorandum Regarding Present Events in the Orient", 1927 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Reports re: China Famine Relief, 1928 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - "Communism and Chinese Nationalism," "Kiangsi Annual Report 1929-30," "Politics and the Red Cross Report," "The Mind's Relation to the Body", 1929-1930 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - "Report Kiangsi International Famine Relief Committee", 1931 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - "A Suggested Plan for Rural Reconstruction ..." (Original and revised editions), 1933 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - "Methodist Work In and Around Nanchang," "The Johnson Memorial Church Building," "The Kiangsi Christian Service Union" (Introduction by WRJ), 1934-1935 (Box 27, Folder 14)